Pepe Doval

Cell: +34-650-795-886 Email: pepellou@gmail.com

I am a senior software developer with 10+ years of experience, seeking for new places to develop my craft. I'm an advocate for Agile Methodologies and Software Craftsmanship, as well as a very active member of the Spanish Agile community. Despite my leadership skills, my passion is coding.



Education

University of Vigo

Major: Computer Science Engineering

Minor: Physics

Predoctoral studies: Artificial Intelligence

Courses: Pedagogical skills, bioinformatics, graphic design, free software, web frameworks, ...

Skills

Software sculpting skills

Unit testing, pair programming, agile methodologies, full stack.

Personal skills

Ethics, team leadership, professionalism, value oriented.

Experience

Trabeculae E.B.T.

Head of IT/Developer - Ourense, Spain - 2008-2010

- Developed software for building three-dimensional models from bone microtomography
- · Designed and developed core internal software for the company
- Developed a software for medical follow-up of patients after hip surgery

Agil-AZ

CEO/Developer - Santiago de Compostela - 2010-2014

- Run the company from scratch. Managed to hire a small team of developers :-)
- Developed 40+ software projects, mostly for startups
- Mostly web development; also mobile apps and backend
- Explored and perfected the use of different methodologies: Scrum, Kanban, XP, etc.

Hermanos Karapatrov

Software Sculptor - Milladoiro - 2011-2013

- Contributed to 10+ audiovisual projects
- Mostly real time image processing; also some web development and graphic design
- Kanban

SetPay

Full Stack Developer - Santiago de Compostela - 2014-2017

- Contributed to development of front-end and back-end of the core products
- Trained other developers
- · Methodology leader
- · Mostly bank software, Java technologies and Angular
- Scrum

Meneame

Full Stack Developer - Santiago de Compostela - 2016

- Contributed to a couple of experiments for this important Spanish social news website
- · Back-end, front-end and scripting
- Kanban

Optare Solutions

Full Stack Developer - Vigo - 2016-2017

- Front-end for some internal tools
- Back-end, architecture and testing of core tools for important national telephone companies
- · Scripting and middleware for security in communications
- Kanban

thewing.es

Full Stack Developer - Fully Remote - 2017

- Contributed with my craft to this leading website on NBA news in Spanish
- · Helped with infrastructure, security and performance
- Kanban

NoLegalTech

The Tech Guy - Fully Remote - 2018-today

- · I do magic to create what our customers want from their ideas
- · I solve problems
- Mostly web development (full stack)
- Kanban

Hobbies

Chess, Maths, Books, Music Hackathons and Coding Dojos Animal lover Volunteering

Languages

Native: Galician, Spanish

Fluent: English